[music]
[Instructor] Cool, so
we've chosen a Background
for our Project. So, we're good
to get started.
Now, we give the scene
a little bit of life,
so we're going to add a Character
for the Player to control.
So, in our Course Library,
we have our Characters,
and we have the choice
between Farm or Town,
so I'm just going to go
with Farm characters
and... I'll just...
I think that one looks good.
So, we're just going to drag
that into our Hierarchy. Cool!
So, now what we're
going to do is, we're going
to rename this to our "Player,"
just like we did
with some of our other players.
And our farmer is kinda
facing towards the back
and that's not what we want
to do at all.
So, if we just turn the farmer,
let's just say like 90 degrees,
and that looks like...
the farmer is facing forward.
Cool. Perfect! Awesome!
Now, one of the things
that I'm going to do just
because I know
I'm going to need these later is,
I'm actually just going to add
a Rigidbody Component now...
And then I'm also going
to add a Box Collider...
And, let's see where that Box
Collider is. It's very small.
It's on the character's feet,
which is definitely not
where we want that to be.
So, let's bring
that up to about the center
and then we'll make that a little bit
larger,
make the Z a little bit larger
and then we'll just make sure
that the Y is properly set up. Cool!
Looks just about right.
Okay! Awesome!
So, now that we have our Box Collider
set up on our Player,
one of the things
that we're going to do is,
create another Scripts Folder
by right-clicking on Assets,
and we're going to need
a PlayerController Script
to actually move our Player.
And then we'll just make sure
that we attach
our PlayerController Script
to our Player.
Click on the Player Controller (Script),
and make sure it's there. Perfect!
So, now what you're going to do is,
you're going to select
your own Character
and add them to the scene
through the Hierarchy,
that way they are at, 0, 0, 0.
You're going to rotate
your character on the Y-Axis,
so then, that way,
they are facing in the direction
that we want them to.
Make sure you rename
your player character.
Add a Rigidbody to the player
and we're going to keep Gravity on.
Add a Box Collider,
and just make sure
that the Box Collider fits
within the character.
And then you're going to make
a Scripts Folder in Assets
and Create your own
PlayerController Script.
So, now it's your turn.
[music]